

RISHAV CHAKRABORTY

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

☑ chakrabortyrishav048@gmail.com

(+919123160776

in linkedin.com/rishav-chakraborty

github.com/Rishav048

Bokaro steel city, Jharkhand

Portfolio

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development (Full-Time) Masai School | Bangalore July 2022 - Present

B-Tech in Mechanical Engineering Dr. B.C. Roy Eng. College, Durgapur August 2016 - July 2020

Intermediate

Bharat Sen. Sc.School, Kota, Rajasthan March 2015 - May 2016

Matriculation

Aadarsh Vidya Mandir,Bokaro | CBSE March 2013 - April 2014

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- DSA
- ReactGitHub
- Chakra UI
- Typescript

SOFT SKILLS

- Adaptability
- Team Collaboration
- Problem-solving
- Consistency

LANGUAGES KNOWN:

- English (S,R,W)
- Hindi (S,RW)
- Bengali(S)

CERTIFICATIONS

Vocational Training

Mejia Thermal Power Plant | D.V.C July 2019

Vocational Training on CATIA

Indo Danish Tool Room | Jamshedpur January 2018

V.T on CNC Milling

Indo Danish Tool Room | Jamshedpur January 2018

PROFILE SNAPSHOT

A self-motivated, hard-working, and ambitious Full-Stack Web Developer and a good learner with proficiency in JavaScript. Having a Problem-solving mindset, and 1200+ hrs of hands-on experience in developing fully functional E-commerce applications. Looking forward to working as a developer and competent employee in an exciting tech company.

PROJECTS

Clone: Nykaa.com

An e-commerce website to purchase beauty products.

Features:

- Sign-in/Sign-up.
- Landing Page, Carousel & Products Page
- Real-time product filter option & Pagination.
- Users can set products per page.
- Add to cart and remove functionality.

Tech Stack: JavaScript | React | HTML | CSS | Chakra UI | Bootstrap An individual project built by me in the span of 6 days.

Clone: KFC.com

An American online food ordering and delivery platform.

Features:

- Sign-in/Sign-up.
- User authentication
- Landing Page, Carousel & Products page
- Search & filter functionality
- Add to cart and remove functionality.
- Payment Gateway

Areas of responsibility:

- Built the website's products page
- Included search & filter functionality
- Add to cart functionality.
- Helped in making dynamic admin dashboard.

Tech Stack: JavaScript | HTML | CSS

A collaborative project built by a team of 5 executed in 6 days.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Business Research Analyst

Markable Solutions | April 2021 - April 2022

- Use Excel functions to organize and analyze data.
- Create charts, graphs, and presentations for leadership teams.
- Develop recommendations to improve business operations going forward.
- Identify trends and make recommendations for improvements.

Sales Engineer

Minimac Systems Pvt Ltd | August 2020 - April 2021

- Responsible for interacting with the clients and solving their queries.
- Maintaining the records of customer interactions and follow up with the clients.
- Conveying customer technical requirements to the Internal Engineering teams.
- Demonstrating products, services, and solutions to potential clients.
- Identifying the customer's current and future requirements.